This is the solutions video for
本视频将讲解
the linear combination lab that covers checking of vector span.
线性组合 lab 的解决方案 涉及向量张成空间的检查
The first thing we need to do is replace "none" with the "np.linalg.solve" function.
首先 把 None 替换成函数 np.linalg.solve
Then we need to mark this task as "done."
然后用 DONE 标明任务已完成
Notice that the first argument in the function is "set of
注意函数的第一个参数是 set_of_vectors (向量集)
vectors" and the second argument is "vector to check."
第二个参数是 vector_to_check (待检查向量)
If "vector to check" is within the span of "set of
若 vector_to_check 在 set_of_vectors 的张成空间内
vectors" then what's returned is a "vector of scalars" that solves Equation 1.
那就返回解出了方程式 1 的 vector_of_scalars
This means the scalars "A" and "B" in Equation 1
也就是说 方程式 1 中的标量 a 和 b
will be represented by the "vector of scalars" returned by the function.
将以函数返回出的 vector_of_scalars 表示
Otherwise, the function returns the printed statement,
若不在张成空间内 则函数会返回输出语句
"there is no single solution," and
说明没有唯一解
the "vector to check" is not within the span of the "set of vectors."
以及 vector_to_check 不在 set_of_vectors 的张成空间中
To save our code,
要保存代码
we need to click on the "Save" icon.
点击保存图标即可
Then we need to select "Kernel," "Restart &amp; Run all" to run the code and
然后依次选择 Kernel、Restart &amp; Run All
Initialize our updated function so that it
运行代码并初始化更新后的函数
will be used to run the rest of the code in the notebook.
从而确保函数会运行 notebook 剩下的代码
Now let's check to see if our function is working properly.
现在 检查函数的效果
In the code here,
这里的代码
we're checking if vector "t" is within the span
调用了函数 check_vector_span 以便检查向量 t 是否在
of vectors "v" and "w" by calling our function.
向量 v 和 w 的张成空间里
Next we define a second set of vectors to check with "set
接着 定义第二个待检查向量集
of vectors" defined as "vw2" and "vector to check" as "t2."
定义向量集为 vw2 待检查向量为 t2
We call the function with "set of vectors" "vw2" and "vector to check" "t2."
调用上述函数 输入向量集 vw2 和待检查向量 t2
Next we define a third set of "vectors to check" with "set of vectors"
接着 定义第三个待检查向量集
defined as "vw3" and "vector to check" as "t3."
定义向量集为 vw3 待检查向量为 t3
We call the function with "set of vectors" "vw3" and "vector to check" "t3."
调用上述函数 输入向量集 vw3 和待检查向量 t3
Below the coding cell,
在下面的代码单元格中
we find the results of running our updated function.
我们可以找到函数更新后的运行结果
Let's check our results.
我们来检查一下结果
Vector "t" is within the span of vectors "v"
向量 t
and "w." The vector scalars return are "2" and "1."
在向量 v 和 w 的张成空间中 向量标量返回值为 2 和 1
We can check this with our expected results and we see they match.
我们可以对比期望结果 两者一致
With Equation 1, "2" is the value of "scalar a" and "1" is the value of "scalar b."
在方程式 1 里 标量 a 的值就为 2 标量 b 的值就为 1
We can go back to our results and we see that vector
回到结果处
"t2" is not within the span of vectors "v2" and "w2."
我们可以看到向量 t2 不在向量 v2 和 w2 的张成空间里
We also see that vector "t3" is not within the span of vectors "v3" and "w3."
我们还可以看到向量 t3 也不在向量 v3 和 w3 的张成空间里
We can check this with the expected results and we see that they match,
和期望结果进行比较 两者一致
where "t2" and "t3" are not within the span.
t2 和 t3 并不在相应的张成空间里
Because the results match the expected results,
结果和期望结果一样
we know we've coded everything correctly.
可见代码无误
Next, read through the rest of the lab and learn how we
接下来请看 lab 剩下的文本
could have written Equation 1 as a system of
文本指出 我们其实可以把方程式 1
equations and use the same function "check
写成一个方程组 并用同一个函数 check_vector_span
vector span" to solve that system of equations.
来解方程组
You'll also learn that a system of equations always results in
文本还指出 方程组的解通常是三种可能情况中的一种
one of three possible solutions and what those solutions look like graphically.
此外 文本还以图表的形式对这三种情况进行了阐明